Born into poverty. Destined for stardom. He lived the American dream.
La Bamba is a drama, music film directed by Luis Valdez.
Los Angeles teenager Ritchie Valens becomes an overnight rock 'n' roll success in 1958,
thanks to a love ballad called "Donna" that he wrote for his girlfriend.
But as his star rises, Valens has conflicts with his jealous brother, Bob, and becomes haunted by a recurring
nightmare of a plane crash just as he begins his first national tour alongside Buddy Holly.
Ritchie Valens, played by Lou Diamond Phillips.
Donna Ludwig, played by Danielle von Zerneck.
Rosie Morales, played by Elizabeth Peña.
Connie Valenzuela, played by Rosanna DeSoto.
Bob Morales, played by Esai Morales.
Bob Keane, played by Joe Pantoliano.
La Bamba is a 1987 American biographical drama film
written and directed by Luis Valdez.
The film follows the life and short-lived musical career of
American Chicano rock and roll star Ritchie Valens.
The film stars Lou Diamond Phillips as Valens, Esai Morales, Rosanna
DeSoto, Elizabeth Peña, Danielle von Zerneck and Joe Pantoliano.
The film also covers the effect that Valens' career had on the lives of his half-brother
Bob Morales, his girlfriend Donna Ludwig, and the rest of his family.
The film is titled after a traditional Mexican folk song of the same name,
which Valens transformed into a rock and roll rendition in 1958.
In 2017, La Bamba was included in the annual selection of 25 motion
pictures added to the National Film Registry of the U.S.
Library of Congress being deemed "culturally, historically, or
aesthetically significant" and recommended for preservation.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll,
biography, death, dying young, nostalgic.
The tone is emotional.